Algorithms are everywhere.
アルゴリズムはどこにでも存在します。
Whether you are writing software, analyzing a genome,
あなたがソフトウェアを書いたり、ゲノム解析をしたり、
predicting traffic jams, producing automatic movie recommendations, or
交通渋滞を予想したり、自動映画レコメンデーションを開発したり、または、
just surfing the Internet, you're dealing with algorithms.
単純にネットサーフィンをしているときにも、あなたはアルゴリズムを扱っているのです。
Every single branch of computer science uses algorithms, so
計算機科学のありとあらゆる分科がアルゴリズムを使っているので、
a course on algorithms and data structures is an essential part of any CS curriculum.
アルゴリズムとデータ構造のコースというのは、どんな計算機科学カリキュラムでも、欠くことのできない重要な要素となっているのです。
>> It's important that the algorithms we use are efficient
我々の使うアルゴリズムが効率的であることは重要です。
as users want to see the search results in a blink of an eye
なぜなら、ユーザは一瞬で検索結果が見られることを期待しており、
even if they search through trillions of web pages.
それが、たとえ何兆ものウェブページを検索しなくてはならないものでも同じように期待しているからです。
A poorly thought out algorithm could take literally centuries to process all
十分によく考えられていないアルゴリズムは、サーチエンジンによって索引付けされたウェブページやフェイスブックのポストを
the webpages indexed by a search engine or all the Facebook posts.
すべて処理するのに文字通り何世紀もかかってしまうことがあります。
And thus, algorithmic improvements are necessary to make these systems practical.
したがって、アルゴリズムの改善というのは、こういったシステムを実用的にするために必要なものです。
That's why tech companies always ask lots of algorithmic
これが、テクノロジー企業が面接でたくさんのアルゴリズムに関する質問を
questions at the interviews.
する理由なのです。
>> In data science problems, like ranking internet search results,
データサイエンスの問題、たとえばインターネット検索結果のランク付け、
predicting road accidents, and recommending movies to users,
交通事故の予想や、ユーザへのおすすめ映画の仕組みなどは、
advanced algorithms are used to achieve excellent search quality,
高度なアルゴリズムが、非常に質の高い検索や
high prediction accuracy, and to make relevant recommendations.
高精度の予測を達成したり、適切なおすすめをするために使われています。
However, even for a simple machine learning algorithm like linear regression
しかしながら、大容量のデータを処理する単純な機械学習アルゴリズム、たとえば線形回帰でさえも
to be able to process big data is usually a challenge.
一般には難題といえます。
When advanced algorithms such as deep neural networks are applied to
たとえばディープニューラルネットワークなどの高度なアルゴリズムを巨大なデータに
huge data sets they make extremely accurate predictions.
適用すると、きわめて高精度な予想をすることができます。
Recently starting to even outperform humans in some areas of vision and
最近では、視覚や発語認識などのいくつかの分野で、人間を凌駕するように
speech recognition, but getting those algorithms to work in
なってきていますが、そいったアルゴリズムを大きなデータセットに対して、
hours instead of years on a large dataset is hard.
数年単位ではなく数時間単位で動かせるようにするのは大変なことです。
And performing experiments quickly is crucial in data science.
素早く実験が可能であるということも、データサイエンスではきわめて重要なのです。
>> Algorithms are everywhere.
アルゴリズムはどこにでも存在します。
Each of trillions of cells in your body executes a complex and
あなたの体の中にある数兆個もの細胞は、それぞれが複雑だが
still poorly understood algorithm.
よく理解されていないアルゴリズムを実行しています。
And algorithm are the key for
そして、アルゴリズムは重要な生体医学の問題を
solving important biomedical problems such as what are the mutations
解決する鍵となっています。たとえばあなたと私を区別する
that differentiate you from me and how is it they relate to diseases.
変化の因子はなんなのか、どのようにその因子が病気と関わっているのか、などの問題です。
In this specialization you will learn the theory behind the algorithm.
この専門課目では、アルゴリズムの後ろに隠れている理論について勉強します。
Implement algorithm in the programming language of your choice and apply them
あなたの好きなプログラミング言語でアルゴリズムを実装し、実践的な問題に
to solving practical problems such as assembling the genome from millions
適用していきます。たとえば数百万の断片からゲノムを組み立てたりします。
of tiny fragments, the largest jigsaw puzzle ever assembled by humans.
それは人間が出来るジグソーパズルの中でもっとも大きなものです。
>> To conclude, algorithms are everywhere.
最後に、アルゴリズムはどこにでも存在します。
And it is important to design your algorithms and to implement them.
そして自分でアルゴリズムを設計し、実装することは重要なことです。
To turn you into a pro in algorithm design we will give you nearly 100 programming
あなたをアルゴリズム設計のプロにするために、このクラスには100近くもの
assignments in this class.
プログラミングの宿題が用意されています。
Your solutions will be checked automatically, and
あなたの回答は自動的にチェックされます。その中で
you will learn how to implement, test, and
どのようにして、大きく難しい問題を数秒で解けるような速いアルゴリズムを実装し、テストし、
debug fast algorithms solving large and difficult problems in seconds.
デバッグすればよいかを学習することが出来ます。
We look forward to seeing you in this class.
このクラスでお会いできることを楽しみにしています。
We know it will make you a better programmer.
このクラスを通してあなたのプログラミングは上達するでしょう。
>> Algorithms are everywhere.
アルゴリズムはどこにでも存在します。
In fact you just saw five algorithms solving the fundamental sorting problem
実はあなたは今計算機科学の基礎的な並べ替え問題を解決する5つのアルゴリズムを
in computer science, and they all have different running times.
見ていたのです。そしてそのアルゴリズムはすべて異なる実行時間で実行されるのです。
In fact while four of them are about to finish one will take a much longer time.
実際、4つのアルゴリズムがほとんど終わろうかというときに、残りのひとつはまだかなりの時間がかかりそうに見えます。
In this specialization you'll be able to implement all of these algorithms, and
この専門科目では、こういったすべてのアルゴリズムを実装する機会があり、
master the skill of answering both algorithmic and
それによって、次の面接でアルゴリズムやプログラミングの
programming questions at your next interview.
質問に答えられるような技術を習得することが出来るでしょう。